Guide to the Durham Cotton Manufacturing Company Records, 1896-1937 (bulk 1915-1934)
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Durham Cotton Manufacturing Company records 1896-1937 (bulk 1915-1934)
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Durham Cotton Manufacturing Company
45.7 linear feet Extent: 34,302 Items
Durham Cotton Manufacturing Company founded, 1884 by J. A., J. M., and W. R. Odell, W. H. Branson, and Julian S. Carr. Headquarters in Durham, N.C. Dissolved, 1940. Letterpress copybooks, invoices, cancelled checks, check stubs, receipt books, and invoices and accounts from Joshua L. Baily and Co., Philadelphia brokers who sold goods for the company. Most of the material represents the years 1915-1934. Includes information on fluctuations in cotton prices, export trade in cotton cloth, types of cloth and machinery, freight rates, salaries, workers' medical care, tenement rents, stockholders, dividends, and distribution of excess profits.
RL.00345
Language: Material in English
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Durham Cotton Manufacturing Company Records were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library from 1946 to 1959.
Collection Overview
Letterpress copybooks, invoices, cancelled checks, check stubs, receipt books, and invoices and accounts from Joshua L. Baily and Co., Philadelphia brokers who sold goods for the Durham Cotton Manufacturing Company, headquartered in Durham, N.C. Most of the material represents the years 1915-1934. Includes information on fluctuations in cotton prices, export trade in cotton cloth, types of cloth and machinery, freight rates, salaries, workers' medical care, tenement rents, stockholders, dividends, and distribution of excess profits.
Subject Headings
Joshua L. Baily and Company (Philadelphia, Pa.); Business records; Cotton -- Prices; Cotton textile industry -- North Carolina; Textile industry -- North Carolina; Industries -- North Carolina -- Durham; Industries -- North Carolina; Durham (N.C.) -- History
Contents of Collection
- Financial Papers Series, 1896-1937 (bulk 1915-1934), (47 boxes)
  - Monthly Accounts, 1916 Oct.-1921 (Box 1)
  - Monthly Accounts, 1922-1925 (Box 2)
  - Financial Statement, 1916 (Box 3)
  - Monthly Accounts, 1915-1916 Oct. (Box 3)
  - Monthly Accounts, 1926-1928 (Box 4)
  - Monthly Accounts, 1929-1931 (Box 5)
  - Monthly Accounts, 1932- 1934 Feb. (Box 6)
  - Monthly Accounts, 1934 Mar.-Dec. (Box 7)
  - Invoices, 1932 June, July, Nov., Dec., 1933 July (Box 8)
  - Invoices, 1933 Jan.-June (Box 9)
  - Invoices, 1933 Aug.-Dec. (Box 10)
  - Invoices, 1934 Jan.-Feb. (Box 11)
  - Invoices, 1934 Mar., May (Box 12)
  - Invoices, 1934 June-Aug. (Box 13)
  - Invoices, 1934 Sept.-Dec (Box 14)
  - Employee Records, 1937 (Box 15)
  - Check Stubs, 1896-1907 (Box 16)
  - Check Stubs, 1906-1918 (Box 17)
  - Check Copy Books, 1918-1919 (Box 18)
  - Cancelled Checks, 1915-1917 (Box 19)
  - Cancelled Checks, 1917-1918 (Box 20)
  - Cancelled Checks, 1919-1920 (Box 21)
  - Cancelled Checks, 1919-1920 (Box 22)
  - Cancelled Checks, 1920-1921 (Box 23)
  - Cancelled Checks, 1921-1922 (Box 24)
  - Cancelled Checks, 1923-1924 (Box 25)
  - Cancelled Checks, 1923-1925 (Box 26)
  - Cancelled Checks, 1926-1927 (Box 27)
  - Orders, 1921 (Box 28)
  - Orders, 1922 (Box 29-30)
  - Cancelled Checks, 1925-1927 (Box 31)
  - Check Stubs, 1929-1930 (Box 32)
  - Orders, 1915-1916 (Box 33)
  - Orders, 1925 (Box 34-35)
  - Orders, 1926 (Box 36)
  - Orders, 1923-1924 (Box 37)
  - Orders, 1924 (Box 38)
  - Orders, 1925 (Box 39)
  - Invoices, 1931 Sept.-Nov. (Box 40)
  - Invoices, 1932 Feb.-Mar. (Box 41)
  - Invoices, 1931 Dec.-1932 Jan. (Box 42)
  - Orders, 1926 (Box 43)
  - Orders, 1926 (Box 44)
  - Orders, 1933 (Box 45)
  - Invoices, 1932 Apr.-May, Sept. (Box 46)
  - Volumes: Receipt Books, 1932-1933 Nov. (Box 47)
- Manuscript Volumes and Other Materials Series
  Financial records in almost one hundred bound volumes, and additional manuscript material (SS-103, SS-104). Please consult with a reference archivist for the locations of these items.